The Princess Sapphire
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Princess Knight,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
First Episode
The Princess Knight
I'm coming! Who is it?
Excuse me, ma'am, have you
by any chance seen a young girl...
...with black hair and blue
eyes, dressed like a boy?
I haven't seen any girl.
Help! Help me! Get
me on my feet, please!
Mrs. Ladybug, maybe
you can help me!
Have you seen a young
girl dressed like a boy?
I really haven't
seen a girl like that.
I've been looking for her for
12 years now without finding her.
Who knows how much
further I'll have to go...!
Take this! And this!
You won't get me, bandits!
Let's get him! How he fights!
Take that! There, you scoundrels!
Come on! I'm not afraid of you!
Let's spray the
revealing liquid on him!
- What are you up to now?
- This!
Damn it, I missed him!
Let's all spray together!
If she's a girl,
she'll change color!
Come on, let's spray!
- Run!
- Quick! - Let's follow him!
Onward, gallop!
Do you want to get your butt
off the ground? Walk, idiot!
Oh, no! Help! I
can't see anymore!
- Where is that damn bastard?
- This way!
No, not in the river!
Where is it less damp?
Here or here? Here or here?
Here! No, here!
Tell your master
not to have me chased anymore!
Away, Opal!
Prince Sapphire, wake up!
It's time to get up! Please!
Help! Ghosts!
They have it out for me! Help!
Good morning, Garigori.
Look how much time you've wasted!
More than half a minute!
Mr. Garigori,
I have been awake for a long time!
So it's time to stop
teasing me!
Good morning, Prince!
It's time to get dressed.
I brought you
clothes suited to your rank.
No! What are you doing, Prince?
No! Stop, please, Prince!
Be good, please!
You rascal!
Doing this to a woman like me.
Where are you going, Prince? Stop!
Come here!
Good morning, Opal!
Are you glad to see me?
Now take my clothes
I didn't feel like
wearing those clothes.
I feel much better in mine.
Now I'm fine!
See you later!
Thank you, little horse!
Greetings to you
and may heaven protect you,
our lord
Sovereign of these lands!
- Greetings!
- May the sun...
...continue to shine
upon your fortunes, and may...
- It's the Prince!
- The black sheep of the realm!
The lord of the castle
of Tenderloin,
grand knight of merit of the kingdom,
the Grand Duke Duralumin
of Duralluminium!
I am pleased to be in the presence
of your august person, Sire.
I too am glad to see you.
- But he sees the King every day!
- You little brat!
I was thinking, regarding
the deer hunting contest,
I want it to be grand
this year!
But is there enough money
for the contest?
Naturally,
it will require more taxes!
I have already prepared the Royal Decree.
You need only sign, Sire.
Give the Grand Duke the Royal Seal!
With it,
you can sign in my place.
- Take that!
- What was that?!
I will return later.
Excuse me...
What a tumble, eh, dad?
Hi, dad!
Sapphire, you must take off
your hat in the Throne Room!
That's better! And why are you
dressed like a poor swordsman?
I like this outfit.
It suits me! I can't stand
those pompous clothes!
Sapphire, remember that
you are the Crown Prince!
You must behave with more dignity!
How dare you address
me by only saying: "Hi, dad!
" Why, dad? What else
was I supposed to say?
First of all, a bow was required.
What's there to laugh about?! Oh, my goodness!
I lost my balance!
Duke Duralumin!
Oh, good morning, Baron Nylon!
It is you!
That brat of a Prince
prevented me from signing...
...in place of the King, the Decree
that increases taxes on the people.
We will teach him a lesson!
Listen, Grand Duke!
I know how to get rid of
the little Prince.
If it were known
that he is actually a girl
he could never again
ascend the throne,
because our law forbids
a woman from reigning as Queen.
I will reveal the secret
and this country will be yours!
If you do so,
you will have wealth and honors from me..
as soon as I am proclaimed King!
A King must not yawn
in public!
He must not even snicker,
cough, or laugh too much.
He must dress with splendor, show himself
always benevolent and never angry,
he cannot remain alone,
but must always be..
...accompanied and aided
by his vassals.
What are you doing? You
shouldn't just look at the pictures!
You must read, if you
want to learn something!
When I was your age, I remember
that I studied very many treatises...
...and I read many more books
than you do!
More than all of these?
Yes, very many!
Hey, Prince, let me out!
You brat, get me out!
Help! Help! Out! Out!
- Mother!
- Sapphire, where are you going in such a hurry?
Don't be naughty! Go back
to your rooms, you must study.
I don't like studying, mother
and I can't stand always being
around old people in the castle!
Sapphire, you shouldn't
say such things!
- I'm leaving! Bye, Mom!
- Sapphire!
My poor little girl!
Where do you want to go?
It is because of the law of this
kingdom that Sapphire is like this now.
It was a season just like this
when she was born.
He is born! He is born!
Rejoice, my loyal subjects!
The long-awaited heir is born!
The Queen has given you a Prince!
I have deceived my people.
I should have announced...
...the birth of a little Princess,
not a little Prince!
You did the right thing!
There was nothing else to be done.
The law forbids a woman
to reign,
so we must make everyone believe
that she is a boy.
My heart breaks!
Why did my husband
announce that she is a boy?
The truth is, he had
no other choice!
If anyone finds out
that a girl was born,
it could be dangerous.
The Grand Duke covets the throne.
we cannot allow him
to seize it.
Your Majesty, as the law demands,
it is time for the Grand Duke...
...to pay homage
to His Highness the little Prince!
Oh, heavens! Wait a
moment! We are not ready yet!
You must show the little Prince!
Don't waste any more time!
What can I do
so he doesn't discover the truth?
Place next to her
a boy's toy.
The Grand Duke will be deceived
Grand Duke, you may enter
to observe...
..His Highness the Little Prince!
I pay homage to His Highness and
wish him to grow up healthy and strong.
In this way they managed
to deceive the Grand Duke..
...and hide the truth
from the court and the people.
From then on, Sapphire was raised
as a boy,
with the complicity of the doctor,
the nurse, and the chamberlain.
Seasons passed,
meanwhile, Sapphire grew up.
She was only allowed games
typical of boys.
The truth was
carefully kept hidden.
Sapphire was slowly raised to
have the mindset of a boy.
So that the kingdom would not fall
into the hands of the evil Grand Duke,
Sapphire grew up without knowing
the small, great joys...
...that bloom
in the female soul.
Poor Sapphire!
How unhappy I feel for you!
How are you, Prince? Are you taking
a solitary walk?
Baron Nylon, I cannot feel
any pleasure in this meeting!
I am sorry, Prince, to hear you
speak this way towards me.
They say you are skilled in fencing. I
would like to measure myself against you.
- Fine!
- Thank you.
- On guard!
- Just the two of us!
Not bad for a boy!
Take this! And this!
A lunge! There! Take that!
Do you like this blow, eh, Baron?
- Remember that it was only a game!
- You lost, it seems!
Do you want another round?
What are you looking at?! I
will win the next contest: archery!
Let's see if you are capable of doing it!
Do you mean this?
Do you like apples?
I've got another idea
for another contest.
An embroidery contest! Whoever makes it
the most beautiful and in the shortest time wins!
How dare you? How
dare you challenge me...
...to a contest in which I'd have
to perform such feminine work?!
Rather, now you will tell me
why you had me followed...
...by your men over
these last few days!
But what are you talking
about? I know nothing!
You are a schemer! Now
get out and leave me in peace!
- Excuse me!
- Who spoke?
- And who might you be?
- My name is Tink.
Tink, you said? And where
on earth did you pop out from?
You know, it's been 12 years
that I've been looking for you!
- You are a girl, aren't you?
- What?!
Yes, tell the truth! I
know that you are a girl.
It's not true, I'm not a girl!
And I tell you that you are!
No, I told you I'm not!
Do you mean to say you're not a female?
Alright, fine. But
how do you know?
Well, you see...
it's just that I...
...you were an angel.
- You were an angel?!
I was a real angel,
before becoming a boy.
Vengo dal Paradiso
I searched for you a lot
before managing to find you!
I was sent to make you
a sweet girl, you know?
You want to make me
a sweet girl?!
Listen, if you want,
you can even try,
but I'm very much afraid that you
will never succeed in this goal!
I, on the other hand, am sure
that I will succeed!
Go away!
- We'll see each other one of these days!
- Keep my secret!
Of course, don't worry!
What a bunch of good-for-nothing
idiots!
I am ashamed that my henchmen
are proving to be so incompetent!
Aren't you ashamed of having
gotten yourselves thrown into the river...
...by that stupid brat?!
Silence, idiots!
Did you use the sword
...that sprays that liquid which makes it possible
to tell men from women?
We tried, Baron, but that
liquid had no effect.
Excuse me!... Oh, look!
The liquid is working!
The Baron has changed color!
So, now, he will be sure
of being a boy!
- What a terrible complexion!
- Enough!
Good morning, Baron,
I am the alchemist!
Good! I was waiting for you! Have
you brought the drug I asked you for?
Tell me: is it true that whoever
takes it confesses any of their secrets?
Of course, Baron!
- You, assassins!
- At your command, Baron!
This time we will use this
new drug, understood?
Do you want to make the Prince drink it?
- No, to the Queen.
- To the Queen?!
Yes, exactly! You will
give it to the Queen!
The Queen must know the Prince's secret
better than anyone!
With this drug, finally,
the Queen will reveal to us...
..if Sapphire is a girl
or not.
In the meantime, you will lure
Sapphire into the enchanted forest,
where there is a wolf
that feeds on human flesh!
- It's time! Let's split up!
- Good!
Where did they go?
This way or that way? This way? That way?
I don't see them anymore. Who knows where
those three assassins have hidden!
I have the feeling I'm lost.
And this place doesn't make me
feel at ease at all.
Who is it?
- It's the Duke, Your Grace.
- Hello, Duke Duralumin.
- Do you desire something?
- A merchant has brought me..
...a very rare elixir.
It is very sweet
and I am sure you will like it.
You are very kind, Duke
- Baron Nylon!
- Yes?
- Would you like to taste some?
- No! Well, actually, I...
...for the last few days
I have become a bit of a teetotaler!
- Nonsense! Just a drop!
- Only a drop...
Bravo! That's how you keep
company with Her Grace the Queen.
And now to you, my Queen!
I am truly lost!
And now who knows what
will be the way out of the forest!
It seems to me that
you are lost, young man.
You're right, old woman. Can you
show me which way I should go?
There is a wolf that feeds
on human flesh, in the forest!
Be careful! This wolf has
lived here for 100 years.
...and it is very cunning and fast!
If you go that way,
you'll find a hut...
...where you can take shelter
tonight.
I'll go there! Thank you, old woman!
The drug we put
in the elixir...
...will take effect
within two hours at most.
The Queen will willingly reveal to us
the Prince's secret...
...and she will tell us if he
is actually a girl!
Yes, but you too will reveal
your secrets!
You have also drunk
the drugged elixir!
There is so much dust
in this hut!
These are the wolf's tracks!
My goodness, he must be huge!
But you're Tink!
Do you know you scared me?
Is that how you greet a friend?
I came to warn you...
...that you've been deceived! This
is the hut where the wolf lives!
- What are you saying?
- Yes! That wolf is so clever
...that he sends travelers to this
hut to devour them later.
A robin told me.
See those hats? They belonged
to the people he devoured!
If what you say is true,
then I am lost.
I know that when the wolf realizes
that its prey is a girl,
- it lets her go.
- If you think that for this reason
I'll dress as a girl, you're wrong!
- Would you prefer to be devoured?
- I will never dress as a girl!
There you go! Sapphire, do you know that you are
really so pretty?
If only you knew how ridiculous I feel!
Remember to behave
like a girl!
I can't wait
to get these rags off me!
- The wolf! Here comes the wolf!
- The wolf is coming!
Let him get close and strike
him by surprise! Good luck!
Almost there!
I feel a sharp pain!
• Is there something wrong,
my Queen?
I would like to confide a
secret of mine to someone.
I'm so hungry! And who
the hell is that over there?!
She looks like a girl!
Yes, a girl!
Oh! The wolf!
You mustn't be afraid!
And now what do I do?!
There is nothing more disgusting
than a little girl dying of fear.
Hey, do you like flowers?
Would you prefer a piece of cake?
Don't be afraid of me! I
will be so good to you!
And don't tremble! You make me
nervous! What do you want me to do to stop?
- Eh? What do you want?
- I just need you to become smaller.
Is this okay?
No! You have to become even
much smaller!
- Like this?
- Yes.
I've got you! I will stop you
from doing any more harm!
You tricked me! And it's
over for you, damn little girl!
Now I will kill you!
My paw! No! Not my paw!
Take that!
- Again!
- Not my paw!
Take this!
My nose! My nose!
No! Not the fire! Not the fire!
No!
Well done, Sapphire! You
did it! You defeated the wolf!
The secret I would like to
confide concerns Sapphire.
Here we go! The Queen is
about to reveal the secret!
Finally I will know
if the Prince is a boy!
I must confess to you
that actually Sapphire is...
Come on!
- Yes, I will say it!
Sapphire - What, Queen?
I too, my Queen, have a
secret to reveal! Yes, yes!
I will tell you: the Grand Duke
has put a drug in the elixir...
...which will force you to reveal if
the Prince is truly a boy!
If you confess that he is not,
the Grand Duke will be able to seize power...
Shut up! You've ruined everything!
What's happening, Baron?
The Queen is about to reveal
whether you are male or female,
because she drank a drug
that the Grand Duke gave her!
What a schemer!
Let's go, Opal!
- What did you do to my mother?
- Nothing special.
- Go away!
- My regards!
- I was about to reveal your secret!
- Yes, I know, Mother.
But we will continue to pretend
that I am a boy,
until in our kingdom
there are no more villains!
My little girl!
And so the story ended.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP